Examinee Number 20, come forward.
The knight selection exam is the
empire's largest annual event.
Go get 'em!
Come on, man! I've bet it all on you!
The official name of the nation everyone
calls "the empire" is the Meeres Empire.
"Meeres" is an ancient  word
meaning "warrior."
Indeed, in the Meeres Empire,
a nation of warriors,
military might is the one and only
path to merit-based success,
and that success is decided
by the knight selection exam.
The exam draws the attention
of many in the empire,
but this year, in particular,
sees a prince personally serving as
the head judge, a first in history.
People have gathered at the venue
in droves for a chance to see him.
Enough!
It's just no use!
Wow... No one can even
lay a finger on him.
So that's the Wise Prince...
This year's exam is
considered far
more exciting than those of past years.
What's important is the outcome.
The knight selection exam is
for choosing worthy soldiers.
I look forward to seeing
what sort of fighter Noah chooses.
Examinee Number 152, come forward!
The sun will be setting soon.
No particularly noteworthy
candidates today, I suppose.
The next test will be
the last of the day!
This... won't... stop me!
I-I'm so sor—
Stop right there!
Master!
Boy, she's really done it.
She actually wounded the prince!
The law's gonna come down hard on her.
Let her go.
B-But, Your Highness, this woman just...
I said, let her go.
O-Of course.
What's your name?
M-My name is Shirley Grantz.
You pass.
I didn't name my standards,
but she's clearly an instant pass.
She passed?
He's forgiving the woman who wounded him?
How generous His Highness is!
Born Blessed, So I'll Obtain Ultimate Power
That's some fine armor.
Do you own it?
Y-Yes. It's been handed down
in my family for generations.
Anyway, um...
what did you mean when you
said... that I passed?
What is my sentence?
For wounding me "by mistake," you mean?
Yes.
There is no such thing.
I told you to attack me, after all.
Stand. Use that thrust on me again.
What?
If you are a knight,
then follow my orders.
If you'll excuse me.
Come.
One... more...
What is this? It won't budge!
This is what I could have done if I'd
really wanted to block your attack.
You did not wound me "by mistake."
A knight's job is to follow orders.
I wanted to see if you would
execute my orders faithfully.
I don't need a knight who's going
to hold back for fear of me.
You came at me in earnest twice,
even after wounding me.
You have what it takes.
Your resolve was that strong?
I, Shirley Grantz, swear my undying
loyalty to you for the rest of my life.
Good.
That exaggerated gesture
I've seen in plays...
It's not formally recognized,
but it gets her intent across.
Name: Thirteenth Imperial Prince Noah Ararat
Sex: Male
Title: Wise Prince
Level: 1
/
∞
HP: F+F
Fire: F
MP: F
Water: E+S
Strength: F+E
Wind: F
Stamina: F+F
Earth: F
Intelligence: F+F
Light: F
Spirit: F+F
Dark: F
Speed: F+F
Dexterity: F+F
Luck: F+F
As far as people go, Shirley
has raised my stats the most.
Pardon me.
Good Croy
Emperor's Doctor
I've brought the doctor.
Now you're here?
This is a bit much.
Thankfully, the strike didn't
hit any bones or organs.
What a relief.
What is it?
Oh, well... I was impressed that a
cut could be treated in that way.
We have no doctors in
my village, you see.
Is that so?
Then what do you do with
your sick and injured?
We have our elder pray for them
or exorcise the root of their illness.
That's quite common in poor villages.
Pardon me.
The quickest way to become a doctor
is to start as an apprentice, right?
Yes.
Shirley, here is your first order.
Y-Yes, Your Highness.
Bring the most clever, hard-working
people from your village to me.
Good, take a few of them as
your apprentices, please.
As you wish.
I'll cover all expenses.
Bring me anyone up to the task of
being a doctor to examine villagers.
Thank you very much!
Knights don't bow like that.
You need to brush up
on knightly etiquette.
Ah, good morning.
G-Good morning.
Did you sleep well?
Not very, since I was
in an unfamiliar room.
I guess even the servants' quarters
are luxurious under a prince.
What do you think?
That sounds nice!
Then perhaps a poor, downtrodden
maiden at a ball...
Oh, that sounds lovely, too!
Reina, what's the matter?
Oh, Zoey.
And Shirley.
We were just imagining what sort of
lady might become our master's bride.
What?!
He's only six years old!
That's very naïve, Shirley.
The other princes were married
before they turned fifteen.
Oh! What about the daughter
of Anju of Almeria?
They're in the master's fief!
Yes! She would be a good fit!
Really, this is so rude.
That's just how loved His Highness is.
You've seen all the cafés that
have sprung up on the street
in front of the house, haven't you?
It's because so many girls gather there
hoping to see the prince, or if they're
very lucky, to catch his eye.
Wh-What a way to live.
Evelyn says all the time
that there is no prince anywhere
who's kinder than our master.
You love him yourself, don't you, Zoey?
You do?
Er, no...
Liar. You've even started
studying magic lately,
all for the master.
Y-You misunderstand!
I just want to be useful to him!
I'm happy just to be able to serve him.
If you'll excuse me.
You have to admire her.
She's just so cute!
The knight selection exam is complete.
Here is the report on this
year's knight selection exam.
Thank you.
Thanks to your screening method,
all of this year's new
knights are excellent.
The knights have expressed
their gratitude.
Tell them that I'm grateful for
their help in running it as well.
You honor us.
Shirley, see our guest out.
At once.
I'll be on my way, then.
Thank you for taking the
trouble to pay us a visit.
We're both knights.
Such formality is unnecessary.
Oh, I beg your pardon!
I see.
He sent you to see off this lowly
knight as part of your training.
His Highness did this for me?
As your senior, let me give
you a word of advice.
You can't go wrong if you stick with him.
You'd best work hard.
I will.
Every time I spin around,
the cold wind blows
In the cold, the folds of my
heart tremble and they cry
My dearest love, if there's an
answer, I will find it on my own
Thank you for inviting me here.
Allow me to congratulate you on the
success of the knight selection exam.
Please fill this night, even with a lie
Because I ended up meeting
you, my heart is singing now
Yes, but this party is to
show my thanks to you two.
Don't waste all your time here.
Go and enjoy yourselves.
Thank you.
Also...
It sings of you, reaching only you
All here are merchants with deep ties
to the Thirteenth Prince's house.
Understand?
Yes. I will go and cultivate
some friendships.
Even in the next life...
I want to meet you
Pardon me.
What is it?
Well... I wasn't sure if
I should pass this along,
but this is addressed to you.
There's nothing written on it.
The guard at the door said the
person who delivered it ran away.
It may contain classified information,
so I brought it just in case.
That was the right decision.
Master!
That's dangerous! Allow me to...
It's all right.
That's all?
It seems there's some unsettling movement
among the remnants of the Almerian rebels.
They still haven't given up?
I don't know.
Whoever delivered this has gone
back to investigate undercover.
I understand.
It's the soldier from back then.
The same one
who informed me of the
rebellion not long ago.
Now that you mention it...
That man did seem to
admire you a great deal.
Yes.
He found out later that the master had
already learned of the rebellion,
but had accepted his warning
without mentioning so.
So he's doing this to repay the debt?
Well done, Your Highness!
No, this is bad.
Playing pretend-spy when you've
had no training is too dangerous.
If he's exposed, he'll be killed.
Oh, no...
My brother Henry should
still be near there.
I'll send a message asking him
to stop this. Get it ready.
O-Of course!
How did it go?
As I expected, he was
exposed and then tortured.
He should have just talked, but he
refused, so they showed no mercy.
My brother's unit got him out,
but he's still unconscious.
This is my fault.
No! There's nothing you could have done!
No, if I'd realized it sooner,
I could have stopped this.
If I had put the emperor's "information
is a weapon" lesson into practice...
Zoey.
Yes?
Send Almeria this message:
"I will spare no expense.
Just don't let that man die.
Whatever he needs, be it money
or a doctor, tell me."
All right, understood.
A single piece of information
is not worth the sacrifice
of such a deeply loyal man.
So many things I've never seen before...
No distractions.
You're on the job.
R-Right!
Are you here to buy something?
Yes.
To thank my brother Henry for
suppressing the rebellion,
and for his letter.
Ah, I see.
In that case, I received a
shipment I'm sure you'll appreciate.
Hey!
What's that?
It doesn't feel the same as the others.
Sharp as always, Your Highness!
You figured it out with
one look, did you?
Is this... glass?
You can make things like
this out of glass?
It was left behind by the uncommonly
skilled artisan, Lindsey.
As it is a lost art now,
only two goddess statues
like this still exist.
All right, I'll take it.
Is 10,000 enough?
More than enough.
There's more than 10,000 in there.
The extra is your reward for
showing me such a fine piece.
Thank you very much!
Hey, there you are.
Oscar Ararat
Eighth Prince
When I came into the store,
they told me you were here.
Brother...
Well, if it isn't
His Highness the Eighth Prince!
Welcome to my store!
I wondered if maybe you'd
find a nice... treasure...
Brother?
A glass goddess statue...
Which means it's Lindsey's?
Y-Yes.
Well, rats. Only two in existence,
and you found the second.
You know where the other one is?
I have it.
I see.
What?!
Y-Your Highness?!
Don't worry. The payment is still yours.
And this is for the trouble.
The second goddess statue was
found, but it was broken.
Spread that rumor.
Just around Cobalt Street is fine.
Incredible. This will greatly raise
the value of my goddess statue.
When it comes to treasure,
the fastest wins.
It may be disrespectful to Lindsey, but if
it makes yours more valuable, it's fine.
There's a big difference between
just one in existence and two.
I didn't achieve that kind of mastery
until I was an adult with my own fief.
I'll thank you later.
See you.
I'll be choosing a different gift.
I still have many to choose from!
What are you thinking about?
Oh, just that it's been nothing but
surprises since I started serving you.
Is that so?
Like today... I understand
your reasoning,
but to destroy such a treasure...
It was only an object.
Real treasures are nothing like that.
Those who risk their lives
to bring me information.
Those who work their hardest
to live up to my expectations.
Those who swear loyalty to me
and dedicate their all to being
useful in any way they can.
Name
Thirteenth Imperial Prince Noah Ararat
Sex
Male
Level
Fire
Water
Strength
Wind
Stamina
Earth
Intelligence
Light
Spirit
Dark
Speed
Dexterity
Luck
The real treasures are people.
Episode 5
People Are Treasures
That includes you.
M-Me, too?!
You seem to have learned a lot
about me in the past few days.
Wow...
He's like the benevolent
rulers I've seen in plays.
Your Highness!
I will follow you
for the rest of my life!
Good.
An adult with a fief...
I want to keep collecting treasures
until I reach that point, too.
Take care.
6 Years Later
Noah Ararat
Age 12
Thank you.
Translation:
Timing:
Editing:
Quality Control:
Becky Cottrill
Edgar Cruz
Gabriella Alabanza
S Bilyeu
Translation:
Timing:
Editing:
Quality Control:
Becky Cottrill
Edgar Cruz
Gabriella Alabanza
S Bilyeu